PERSONAL INFORMATION

Nchoolwe Progress Sinampande



- 3609 Mainway Meadows, 00263 Harare (Zimbabwe)
- 0775928950
- https://snapsmicrosystems.co.zw/
- WhatsApp +263775928950

Sex Male | Date of birth 31/01/1995 | Nationality Zimbabwean

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am 25-year-old young Zimbabwean who comes from Binga. I am currently working as a GIS and Remote Sensing Specialist at Chinhoyi University of Technology. I hold a class 2.1 Bsc Honors Geography Degree in Human Environment awarded by the University of Zimbabwe. For my dissertation, I specialized on the Spatial data infrastructure and designed a geoportal prototype. I worked for Scientific and Industrial Research and Development

Center (SIRDC) in Harare under the Geoinformation and Remote Sensing Institute (GRSI) from August, 2017 to July 31, 2018 as an intern. During that time, I participated in Agricultural Mechanization Projects, mapping Ruwa Local Board Cadaster including creating subsequent spatial database, GIS trainings and was awarded a Certificate in GIS and Remote Sensing. I have worked as a consultant individually and partnering with other professionals in several consultancy projects.

WORK EXPERIENCE

16/09/2019-Present

GIS and Remote Sensing Specialist

Chinhoyi University of Technology 00263 Chinhoyi (Zimbabwe) https://www.cut.ac.zw/home/cut/

- Development and maintenance of GIS data resources to be utilized within the department and for public access.
- Data gathering and compilation, Geographic Information Systems (GIS), GPS, mapping, and data analysis.
- Perform varied data gathering and entry to create, maintain, display and update Geographic Information Systems databases, coverage, and linkages to various GIS databases.
- Produce accurate maps and other representations of data for public use and fieldwork activity.
- Go out in the field to visually locate items to resolve conflicting information and ensure the accuracy
 of data.
- Record and document details of map updates, additions and/or deletions.
- Information extraction (satellite image classification and analysis)
- Damage and Risk Assessment using Remotely sensed data
- Designing practical for students in related to GIS, Remote Sensing, Data Analysis and Web mapping

Business or sector Education

11/6/2

2019 Database designer Consultant

Ntengwe for Community Development (NGO), Vic Falls (Zimbabwe) https://ntengwe-dev.org/

- Designing of Ntengwe Database Management System for Beneficiaries
- Designing of a Mobile data collection system linked with QGIS Software for Spatial Data Analysis
- Training Ntengwe officials on utilizing geographic information system

Business or sector NGO

08/08/2018-15/08/2018

GEO Database and Mapping Consultant

Ministry of Energy and Power Development 00263 Harare (Zimbabwe)

http://www.zim.gov.zw/government-ministries/ministry-energy-and-power-development

- Designing of a Geo-database to store data for the Energy Projects by the Ministry of Energy and Power Development such as Bio-gas digester and not limited to solar power plant distribution
- Installation of Open data kit (ODK) on a Local based server
- Training of the Energy Sector Officials on GIS and Mobile Data Collection

Business or sector Ministry of Energy

24/08/2017-06/07/2018

Environmental Science and Geo-informatics intern

Scientific and Industrial Research and Development Centre 1574, Alpes Road Scam Way, Harare, 00263 Harare (Zimbabwe), 00263 Harare (Zimbabwe)

http://www.sirdc.ac.zw/

Digitizing cadaster maps

Designing mobile data collection forms

Creation of Geodatabase and designing custom geo webservers for City Councils

Data collection using GPS

Participating in Environmental impact assessment projects

Processing Remote sensed images

Facilitating GIS and Remote Sensing training

Business or sector Research Institute

2017 Mobile Data Collection Designer and Facilitator

Sight Savers, Gokwe (Zimbabwe)

https://www.sightsavers.org/

- Designing of Mobile Data Collection tool to analyze the coverage and distribution of Antazoline and xylometazoline
- Assisting in report writing and data analysis during evaluation

Business or sector NGO

Nchoolwe Progress Sinampande

06/12/2016-22/12/2016

Mobile Data Collection tool Designer and Survey enumerator

World Vision Organization, Harare (Zimbabwe)

https://www.wvi.org/zimbabwe

- Designing of the ODK Mobile Data collection form for the Baseline survey for End course immunization
- Field data collection enumerator

Business or sector NGO

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

24/08/2015-20/09/2019

Bachelor of Science Geography Honors Degree in Human

Environment

University of Zimbabwe

Mt Pleasant, 00263 Harare (Zimbabwe)

https://www.uz.ac.zw/

30/10/2017-03/11/2017

Certificate of Training in Geo-information Science and Remote Sensing

Seriality

Scientific and Industrial Research and Development Centre 1574, Alpes Road Scam Way, 00263 Harare (Zimbabwe)

http://www.sirdc.ac.zw/

2018-2019

Solo Learn Online Programming Certificate

Solo Learn online learning https://www.sololearn.com/

Python 3 JavaScript PHP

SQL

PERSONAL SKILLS

Mother tongue(s)

Tonga

Foreign language(s)

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
C2	C2	C2	C1	C2

English

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user - B1 and B2: Independent user - C1 and C2: Proficient user Common European Framework of Reference for Languages - Self-assessment grid

11/6/2 Page 3 /

Curriculum vitae

Communication skills

good communication skills gained through my experience as a consultant excellent contact skills with students gained through my experience as GIS specialist at a University

Job-related skills

- good command of quality control processes (currently responsible for GIS and Remote Sensing computer Lab)
- Data processing.
- Communication skills.
- · Reporting skills.
- Productivity.
- · Confidentiality.
- Documentation skills.
- Equipment maintenance.
- Problem solving

Digital skills

SELF-ASSESSMENT						
Information processing	Communication	Content creation	Safety	Problem- solving		
Proficient user	Proficient user	Proficient user	Proficient user	Proficient user		

Digital skills - Self-assessment grid

Driving licence

R

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

References

1) Dr P.Tagwireyi

(PhD, OSU, USA, MEPP, UZ, ZW, BSc, Hon, BUSE, ZW, Dlp Ed, UZ.ZW)

Senior Lecturer (Spatial Ecology, GIS Applications)

Dept of Geography and Environmental Science Geoinformation Science and Earth Observation

Centre of Excellence Mobile: +263783383690 Email: tagwireyip@gmail.com

2) Prof. P. Taru

Chairperson: Department of Environmental Conservation and Geoinformatics

Chinhoyi University of Technology Mobile: +263777 401 738 Email: philiptaru@yahoo.ie

11/6/2 Page 4 /